The will was sent back to the capital
遺詔が都に伝えられる
Xie Xuan was ordered to assist in governance
謝玄は政務を補佐する命を受けた
Crown Prince Sikong Sheng successfully ascended the throne
太子司空が順調に即位する
And changed the era name to Taian the following year
そして翌年元号を泰安に改めた
Prince of Yan, how have you been?
燕王お元気でしたか
However, many military generals led by Zhu Yuanzhi
しかし朱元之を首とする複数の軍関係者
Still frequently visited Sikong Xu
しかしそれでも司空旭を頻繁に訪ね続けていた
Causing Sikong Sheng much dissatisfaction
それによって司空盛はこれに多くの不満を抱いた
Regent Minister Xie Xuan and his faction
摂政大臣謝玄とその党羽
Then began to continuously suppress Zhu Yuanzhi in court
すぐに朝廷で朱元之を絶えず圧迫し始めた
And weakened Zhu Yuanzhi's military power and the Second Prince's faction
朱元の兵権や二皇子たちの勢力を弱める
General Zhu, please
朱将軍どうぞ
Please
お願いします
General Zhu served Father with utmost dedication
朱将軍は父皇に対して尽力して忠義を尽くした
Fought all his life
生涯を戦う
Your Majesty suspects whom
陛下は誰を疑っていますか
Should not be General Zhu
朱将軍でもあるべきではない
These years
これらの年
Your Highness has been friendly with your servant
殿下は私と親しくしています
Why pretend to be confused?
それならわざと知らないふりをする必要はないでしょう
Your Highness has been fighting abroad for so many years
殿下はこれまで何年も外で遠征しておられます
With outstanding military achievements
功績が顕著だ
Everyone sees it
みんなが目にしている
This realm should have been yours
この世界は本来あなたのものです
How heroic the late Emperor was
先帝はかつていかに勇壮であったことか
How indecisive and cowardly the current Son of Heaven is
今の天子は一体どれほど優柔で臆病なのか
I see Your Highness has the late Emperor's legacy
私は殿下に先帝の遺風を見る
Only Your Highness can realize the late Emperor's grand vision
殿下だけが先帝の偉業を成し遂げることができます
We are willing to follow Your Highness to the death
我々は殿下に従うことを命がけで誓います
Today I'll act as if General Zhu never said this
今日のこの言葉は朱将軍が言わなかったことにしておこう
Your Highness
殿下でんか
Your Highness, this old minister is of this age
殿下老臣もこの年になりました
Each day I can help you is one less day
あなたを助けられる日が1日過ぎるごとに1日少なくなる
But now we only have eight thousand men
でも今私たちはわずか八千人しかいません
When the late Emperor rose up
当年先帝が挙兵された時
We had only a few hundred men
私たちの手下はせいぜい数百人しかいません
A few hundred men still struck first
数百人が同じように先手を打つ
But
しかし
You insist on waiting until everything is too late
あなたはすべてが手遅れになるまで待たなければならないのですか
And regret it then?
悔やんでも遅すぎますか
If I can achieve great things
もし私が大きなことを成し遂げることができれば
General Zhu will be credited with the first merit
朱将軍が最初の功績を記録すべきだ